Guide to the Robert B Hoy Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert B Hoy papers
1949-1980
SC0894
Hoy, Robert B.
3 Linear feet
Collection includes manuscripts, project files, reports, correspondence, and subject files related to his career. Series I pertains to his work with the New Jersey Zinc Company, 1950-59. Series II contains materials related to programs conducted in the Dept. of Earth Sciences at the Stanford Research Institute, 1949-64; subjects include geology, geochemistry, oceanography, and salt domes, especially the Winnfield salt dome in Winn Parish, LA. Series II pertains to the exploration programs of AMAX Exploration, Inc., 1961-80.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Robert B. Hoy graduated from Lafayette College (Pennsylvania) in 1937 and pursued a career as a geologist, working with the New Jersey Zinc Company, Stanford Research Institute, and AMAX Exploration, Inc.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes manuscripts, project files, reports, correspondence, and subject files related to his career. Series I pertains to his work with the New Jersey Zinc Company, 1950-59. Series II contains materials related to programs conducted in the Dept. of Earth Sciences at the Stanford Research Institute, 1949-64; subjects include geology, geochemistry, oceanography, and salt domes, especially the Winnfield salt dome in Winn Parish, LA. Series II pertains to the exploration programs of AMAX Exploration, Inc., 1961-80.
Access Terms
AMAX Exploration, Inc.; Hoy, Robert B.; New Jersey Zinc Company.; Stanford Research Institute.; Geochemical prospecting.; Geochemistry.; Salt domes--Louisiana.
Collection Contents
- New Jersey Zinc Company (Pennsylvania), 1950-1959; Series 1
  - Annual report, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Comptrollers: subject files and notes, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - “Fault in Paleozoic Rocks Near Frederick, Maryland,” November 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - “Frequency Distribution of Combined Zinc-Lead-Copper Values in Soils of the Eastern United States,” paper for 20th International Geological Congress, 1956-58 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - “Friedensville, Pennsylvania: the New Jersey Zinc Company Geology and Development,” report by M. S. Childs, Nov. 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Geochemical prospecting, bibliography, 1950-53 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Geochemical research, 1953-54 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Geochemistry – general, 1953-56 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Geochemistry – soils, 1952-55 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - “Geology of the Friedensville Zinc Mine,” Dec. 1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hydrothermal deposition (subject file), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Metallogenic Province investigation, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Organizational charts, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania – Lehigh Valley, photographs of geologic maps, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sales – pricing and statistics, 1953-55 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - “Spectrochemical Analysis Method for Determination of Minor Element Content in Geochemical Applications,” research department memo, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Tennessee – Mississippi embayment sediments, exploration reports, 1957-58 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Stanford Research Institute, 1949-1964; Series 2
  - Accounting systems, 1957-59 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - American Mining Congress, 1958-62 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - California Senate Fact Finding Committee on Natural Resources: Hearing, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - “Control and Handling of Classified Information: Provisional Instructions for Staff Members,” May 1963 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1959-63 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - “Economic Study of Mining Sea-Floor Manganese Nodules: Final Report, Prepared for International Nickel Company of Canada, Ltd.” Dec. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Employee benefit booklets, 1954-63 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Equipment transfers, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Forms and procedures, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - General Motors, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Geochemical Prospecting, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Geochemical research program, 1959-60 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Geochemistry – annual review of activities, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Geohydrology program, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Geologic developments, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Geological Society of America, 1958-59 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Geology exploration, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Gold recovery program, 1961-63 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Idea File (research proposals, clippings), 1958-62 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - “India in Tomorrow’s World,” 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - “Industrial Minerals: 1960-61,” presented to American Mining Congress by Richard M. Foose, Sept. 1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - International Conference on Saline Deposits, National Academy of Sciences – National Research Council, Nov. 2-23, 1962, program and correspondence, 1962-63 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - “Investigation of Visual and Photographic On-Site Inspection Techniques for the Detection of Underground Nuclear Explosions,” report, March 1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Lafayette College News Report, June 1959 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Linear Electron Accelerator, Sand Hill Site, Stanford University, preliminary geological reports, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Long Range Planning Report Service, 1959-62 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Magnetite, research proposal, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Muroc Clay Company – Sun-Ray Samples, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - News Bulletin (Research for Industry) and Newsletter (SRI Highlights), 1956-61 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Outside business activities of staff members, memorandum, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Personnel, ca. 1958-64 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Poulter Laboratories, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Project Cowboy (Carey Salt Mine, Winnfield, LA): salt analysis, 1959-62 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - “Project Oilsand: A Proposed Experiment in the Peaceful Use of Nuclear Energy in the Athabasca Area, Alberta, Canada,” reports and exhibits, July 1959 (1 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Project Oilsand, 2 of 4 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Project Oilsand, 3 of 4 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Project Oilsand, 4 of 4 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Purchase orders and requisitions, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Quadrupole Mass Spectrometer, research proposal, operating manual, 1962-63 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Recruitment, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Remote sensing, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Research, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Salt Domes (notes, clippings, maps), 1951-62 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Saskatchewan Study, background materials, 1957-59 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Seaweed – bibliography, ca. 1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Seaweed – exploration (Scotland, Sargasso Sea, California), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Seismic Symposia, 1960-61 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Shreveport Geological Society Spring Field Trip: Interior Salt Domes and Tertiary Stratigraphy of North Louisiana – guidebook, April 1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Solar Furnace, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Sources of information, 1960-61 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Stanford University School of Mineral Sciences, program booklet, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - “Structure of Winnfield Salt Dome, Winn Parish, Louisiana” – paper, 1961, and published version, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - “Structure of Winnfield Salt Dome, Winn Parish, Louisiana,” photographs and illustrations (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - “Structure of Winnfield Salt Dome, Winn Parish, Louisiana,” photographs and illustrations (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Travel expenses, 1959-63 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - “Value of Mineral Commodities: Final Report, Prepared for Tidewater Oil Company, Dec. 1961 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - “The Winnfield Louisiana Salt Dome,” master’s thesis by Harriet Cameron, June 1949 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Winnfield Salt Dome (Louisiana): correspondence, 1961-63 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Zinc, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- AMAX Exploration, Inc., 1961-1980; Series 3
  - Annual report, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Arizona porphyry copper trip (3rd biennial) – guidebook, field notes, correspondence, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Baja and Mexico Economic Geology Field Trip (Univ. of Arizona) May 1975 – guidebook (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Baja and Mexico Economic Geology Field Trip (Univ. of Arizona) May 1975 – guidebook (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - “Cadastro de Recipiendários de Publicações DNPM” (Brasil-Pro Unidade de Federação), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Columbium and Tantalum – clippings, memorandum, 1967-69 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - “Exploration Trends for Ore,” published article with related correspondence, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Florida Pebble Phosphate Field, 1966-76 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Fort Worth Basin Exploration Project (Oceanic Exploration Company), ca. 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - “Molybdenum Potential in Bolivia,” report, Jan. 1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Nickel, 1961, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - “Notes on the potential for ocean mining,” study, March 1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - “Present and Possible Future Sources of Vanadium,” report, March 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - “Tantalum Investigation and Exploration,” report, April 1968 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Titanium, memorandum, May 1967 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - “Trona Deposits in the Green River Basin: Sweetwater, Uinta, and Lincoln Counties, Wyoming” (USGS Open-File Report 79-737), 1979 (1 of 5) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - “Trona Deposits in the Green River Basin: Sweetwater, Uinta, and Lincoln Counties, Wyoming” (USGS Open-File Report 79-737), 1979 (2 of 5) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - “Trona Deposits in the Green River Basin: Sweetwater, Uinta, and Lincoln Counties, Wyoming” (USGS Open-File Report 79-737), 1979 (3of 5) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - “Trona Deposits in the Green River Basin: Sweetwater, Uinta, and Lincoln Counties, Wyoming” (USGS Open-File Report 79-737), 1979 (4of 5) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - “Trona Deposits in the Green River Basin: Sweetwater, Uinta, and Lincoln Counties, Wyoming” (USGS Open-File Report 79-737), 1979 (5of 5) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Tungsten, clippings and notes, 1956-74 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - “Tungsten in Western U.S.” – report and related correspondence, 1969-72 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - “U.S. coastal and Offshore Mineral Deposits,” report by E. J. Langey, May 1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Vanadium, clippings and memorandum, 1967-71 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Wyoming: Sweetwater County property map, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Wyoming: Trona, Green River Basin, Prospecting map, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Zirconium, memorandum, June 1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)